<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Billy&#39;s Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://billy.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Billy&#39;s Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://billy.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Food-Efficient: Pour-Over Coffee</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/coffee/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I attended a wonderful Interintellect Salon on Talking about Money, where we talked about everything from the philosophy of money, to why there seems to be so much financial illiteracy, to the credit card ecosystem, to the US Tax Code.
A recurring point was that good financial advice can be hard to find, and you might not even know where to start looking. And personal finance has been something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to write about for a while now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Week&#39;s Inspiration: VTubers</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/vtubers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 01:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/vtubers/</guid>
      <description>I recently stumbled upon the phenomenon of VTubers, and honestly I&amp;rsquo;m a bit obsessed.
&amp;quot;Eekum bokum.&amp;quot;
-Inugami Korone, 2020 pic.twitter.com/DEL4krzKFy
&amp;mdash; Tylor (@theSirToasty) September 1, 2020 
VTubers, short for Virtual YouTubers, are what you&amp;rsquo;d get if anime characters suddenly came to life and also became Content Creators. They&amp;rsquo;re real people playing a persona using digital, anime-like avatars (not to be confused with influencers that are CGI + ML models).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Growth, and Viruses</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/exponential-growth-and-viruses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 19:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/exponential-growth-and-viruses/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;On Day 1 you start with 1 penny. On Day 2 you double it and have 2 pennies. On Day 3 you double that and have 4 pennies. Repeat. How much money do you have on Day 30?&amp;rdquo;
Most people have been asked this question at one point or another.
It’s memorable; in part because the idea of doubling the size of your bank account day after day sounds like something you’d sign up for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo - Food, Coffee, Games</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/tokyo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/tokyo-2019/</guid>
      <description>In the span of two weeks, 3 friends asked me for Tokyo recommendations from my trip earlier this year. So I&amp;rsquo;m putting those recommendations here as a sort of log / for future reference.
Here are some general tips on how to travel to Tokyo. The rest is all about food, coffeeshops, and games (the majority of time spent during my recent trip).
Inspired by my friends&amp;rsquo; recs (thanks Ophelia), The Cup and the Road blog, and the random Swiss guy who told me about Kanemasu over tempura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Minimum Viable Blog</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/minimum-viable-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 22:26:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/minimum-viable-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by how great writers can break apart complex systems, stir up emotions, and build worlds. Writing is an especially important skill now, as we live and breathe email, iMessage, and Slack. Where you can find friends, and even a tribe, solely via Twitter.
As with anything I find interesting, I wanted to try doing it myself. With writing, though, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure where or how to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:54:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a first post!
In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a bit about me and here are some of my favourite links.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>