<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Billy&#39;s Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://billy.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Billy&#39;s Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 23:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://billy.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #9: Good Work</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 23:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/9/</guid>
      <description>This past May, I started feeling like I&amp;rsquo;d been doing Fun Projects for long enough. Since July 2023 I&amp;rsquo;d been fighting (with love) my urge/anxiety around needing to feel productive, make money, and get back to self-sufficiency, by reconnecting to my sense of Fun and doing Fun Projects.1 But after ~10 months of this, I was feeling a bit hedonistic, and I was suddenly motivated again to work on my career.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Was Your Trip?</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/how-was-your-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 22:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/how-was-your-trip/</guid>
      <description>It happens every time now, when I return from traveling. The moment I step out of the uber and onto the street below my apartment, I feel like I never left. Like I&amp;rsquo;m resuming a game that I paused so I could use the bathroom quickly. And it&amp;rsquo;s not just like I&amp;rsquo;m picking up where I left off, but it&amp;rsquo;s like I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten what it&amp;rsquo;s like to have been away. To have been someplace different.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on Masculinity</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/masculinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/masculinity/</guid>
      <description>I am working on a full blog post about Masculinity, but the scope of that post just keeps growing and growing… so in the name of publishing more, I&amp;rsquo;m putting out this brief outline of points in the meantime.1
A while ago I saw someone asking about masculinity on threads.net, and here was my own general answer:
Maybe this is really all that needs to be said. Focus your time and energy on what you want to see more of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walls</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/walls/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started to notice a recurring set of Walls I keep running into in life, a bit like level caps on a video game character but not exactly. In a sense they are self-sustaining, in that they are sustainted by me (or part of some past version of me that I hold onto that was adaptive but has now become maladaptive).
I run into these Walls, recognize them, greet them and say &amp;ldquo;Hello again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overthinking: Vacation</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/overthinking/vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/overthinking/vacation/</guid>
      <description>Since its inception, my France trip has sort of been a plan of conflict.
A chance to watch the Olympics live? Hell yeah! 1
A chance to live out a childhood dream of residing in France for a couple months? Hell yeah!!
Except August is also the most excited I&amp;rsquo;ve been to go all-in on spinning up a coaching business… which I can&amp;rsquo;t really do while I&amp;rsquo;m on vacation in France.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overthinking: Having a Comments Section</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/overthinking/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/overthinking/comments/</guid>
      <description>I like my static HTML generator blog. It’s slick, it’s lightweight, I think it’s cute. I can render it on my local without an internet connection and write posts on airplanes like I&amp;rsquo;m doing with this one.
But one thing this blog doesn’t have is a (nice and easy way to set up a) comments section.1
But also, who tf is even reading this blog lol such that there would be a lively comments section.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #8: Year One</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/8/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been just over one year now since I went on sabbatical, and I wanted to write some sort of &amp;ldquo;Year One&amp;rdquo; update post. But what I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to happen was for me to get stuck making something Serious or Formal in order to Properly celebrate the milestone. So here I am, writing something quick and loose so I can just get something out into the world.
A quick summary of my one year on sabbatical:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Figure Out What You Like?</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/what-you-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/what-you-like/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this post, and the question &amp;ldquo;What do I love?&amp;rdquo;
(If you like, you can skip ahead to the prescriptive stuff.)
I feel like some people will find this question absurd, because to them it&amp;rsquo;s obvious. &amp;ldquo;You like what you like,&amp;rdquo; or, &amp;ldquo;you just know, you can feel it.&amp;rdquo; But you only ask the question when it becomes a question; there are times when the answer is very not-obvious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #7: Learning How To Be Happy</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/7/</guid>
      <description>Up until a month ago, I would explain what I was doing on sabbatical by telling people something like &amp;ldquo;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m going to the gym, and then besides that I&amp;rsquo;m mostly doing fun creative projects like writing, drawing, and playing the drums.&amp;rdquo; Because that&amp;rsquo;s what I did. For the past few months, from Feb thru May, all I focused on was getting into a rhythm again of Doing Stuff that I enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #6: Is This It?</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/6/</guid>
      <description>Writing my previous blog post took a lot out of me, to the point where I started looking forward to being done with the post halfway through the writing process. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I wrote it, but I&amp;rsquo;m also glad it&amp;rsquo;s over with. After publishing the post, I took a week off from writing. I still drew portrait studies and practiced the drums, but I filled the extra time with books, video games, and… just pondering what else to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Fit Person</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/becoming-a-fit-person/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/becoming-a-fit-person/</guid>
      <description>All my life I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with losing weight and working out consistently. My motivations have varied from parental pressure, to self-pressure, to wanting to look good naked, to wanting to jump higher when I play volleyball so I can absolutely slam down the ball. But I was never really able to make significant progress.
I was stuck. Two years ago I thought I&amp;rsquo;d found a path to cutting weight consistently and I was optimistic about the future again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Stages of Change</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/the-stages-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/the-stages-of-change/</guid>
      <description>One of my absolute favourite mental models is the one that describes change, called Prochaska&amp;rsquo;s Transtheoretical Model of Behaviour Change.
Essentially, it describes the stages of change as:
Pre-contemplation Contemplation Preparation Action Maintenance Pre-contemplation is when you aren&amp;rsquo;t even considering making a change, or you&amp;rsquo;re not aware that you are.
Contemplation is when you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about change, toying with the idea, making pros/cons lists for fun, etc. &amp;ldquo;What if I was like this instead, what would that be like?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(How to) Love The Grind</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/love-the-grind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/love-the-grind/</guid>
      <description>There are generally two hurdles to overcome when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to Do The Thing:
Getting started Keeping at it (without burning out) It&amp;rsquo;s easier to start Doing The Thing if you have an idea you&amp;rsquo;re excited about, an idea that sounds Fun to you.
Similarly, once you&amp;rsquo;ve started, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to keep Doing The Thing if the process is Fun. If the grind is Fun.
This is, I think, what&amp;rsquo;s actually at the core of the popular quote: &amp;ldquo;Choose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023: Year In Review</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/2023-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 22:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/2023-review/</guid>
      <description>See my review of 2022 here.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this in the early days of January 2024, and it feels&amp;hellip; odd. The energy at the end of the year that I love so much, the kind that makes you want to hug your loved ones tight and reflect on life, that energy is dissipating. It&amp;rsquo;s almost all gone now, in favour of vivacity for the new year and new beginnings. But I really wanted to reflect on 2023, so in spite of the timing we&amp;rsquo;re doing this now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #5: Self-Love</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 23:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/5/</guid>
      <description>Covers Nov 2023 to Jan 2024.
After the dust settled in October, my experiences and my new mindset coalesced into these two goals:
Continue to do the creative work that I love, and do whatever I need to in order to sustain this; while in the background:
Rewire myself away from grasping for external validation of my work as a necessary component of my worth, and toward cultivating an internal wellspring of self-worth</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical: July - October</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/recap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/recap1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on sabbatical since July now. And up until October, something new would shift for me literally every two weeks. This post is intended to be a record of all of those changes, so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget this crazy, wonderful time.
The timeline
How it started July Week 1-2 - Objective #1 - Find a more fulfilling way to work Getting another perspective - Give Your Gift Week 3-4 - Objective #2 - Reconnect with Fun August Week 1-2 - Objective #3 - Meander The neutral zone Week 3-4 - A door appears September Week 1-2 - Descend Week 3-4 - Emerge October Objective #4 - Keep doing creative work How it started ↩︎</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #4: October</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/4/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been chipping away at a big post to map out how my thinking has changed since the start of my sabbatical in July (edit: out now!). But I&amp;rsquo;ve also been getting antsy about not having published anything in over a month. So here&amp;rsquo;s an update for October!
Do The Thing &amp;ldquo;Do The Thing&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Do 100 Reps&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Just Do It&amp;rdquo;
This idea has been like a scalpel for me, continuing to cut through my bullshit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Encounter with The Emptiness</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/emptiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/emptiness/</guid>
      <description>A few nights ago I found myself sitting at my desk with this vague sense of discomfort and uncertainty.
I&amp;rsquo;d made some progress that day on a blog post I&amp;rsquo;d been writing and rewriting for a few weeks now. The progress was good. But I also felt like I had pages of notes and drafts and rewrites scattered all over the floor, and all I was doing was adding new notes and new drafts to the pile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #3: Goals</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/3/</guid>
      <description>While updating my Now Page, I got to thinking about how I would describe what I&amp;rsquo;d like to accomplish on my sabbatical. I wanted a clear-cut answer to a question I&amp;rsquo;d been asking myself for the past two months now: &amp;ldquo;What am I doing? Where is this going?&amp;rdquo;
Here&amp;rsquo;s the excerpt I came up with:
I&amp;rsquo;d love to eventually carve out a way of living and working that&amp;rsquo;s more satisfying for me than my prior experience with the typical corporate path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #2</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/2-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/2-fun/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Everyone has a plan until they get punched in the mouth.&amp;rdquo; - Mike Tyson, modified
Planning is everything, but plans mean nothing. And oh boy did my initial plans go out the window quickly.
The top projects I&amp;rsquo;d planned to work on were: coaching setup stuff, writing blog posts, and writing fiction. But when I started to actually spend time on these things, I found myself feeling kinda miserable. What the heck?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #1</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/1-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/1-doing/</guid>
      <description>Doing the thing I&amp;rsquo;m officially on sabbatical!
I started my leave from work on June 5, but I immediately went on a 2-week vacation to Tokyo. Now I&amp;rsquo;m settled back in, and getting to work. And so, in July 2023, it really begins.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written previously about what I&amp;rsquo;d like to accomplish during my little incubator: in short, writing a lot and starting up some form of tech career coaching. But two weeks in and I already feel a bit unmoored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo - Food, Coffee, Shopping</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/tokyo-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 21:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/tokyo-2023/</guid>
      <description>Last updated on Feb 20, 2024.
Sections Logistics before (flights, lodging, mobile data) Logistics there (transit, cash, restaurants, laundry) Districts Tsukiji Market specifically Food recs Coffee recs Personal Colour Analysis Shopping Logistics before Flights
There are two airports you can fly to: Haneda airport (HND) and Narita airport (NRT).
I’d recommend HND if you have the choice.
HND is closer to Tokyo (45 mins to 1h for ~¥600 by subway) vs NRT (1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Game&#43;</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/new-game-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 22:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/new-game-plus/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s this feature in some video games (usually single-player action/adventure RPGs) that allows the player to start a new playthrough of a game after beating it once, but with some added twists the second time through.
When you begin a New Game+ you venture back out into the game world, but you get to keep some of your progress, items, abilities, or upgrades you acquired during your first playthrough. Coupled with this, the game also becomes more challenging: enemies are stronger, dungeons are harder, and there might be hidden bonus content that becomes available to you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Are You Gonna Travel?&#34;</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/are-you-gonna-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/are-you-gonna-travel/</guid>
      <description>When I tell friends I plan to take a sabbatical later this year, their first question to me is almost always this one. (If it&amp;rsquo;s not their first one, then it&amp;rsquo;s definitely their second.)
And I get the feeling that my answer is a bit weird. What I want to do is kind of the opposite–I want to stay home, hunker down, and create. I jokingly liken it to grinding skill points in a video game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 5/25 Rule</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/5-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/5-25/</guid>
      <description>This one goes out to those of us who are constantly distracted by shiny new ideas.
One guiding rule I had in my 20s was to focus on doing (1) things that I wanted to do, and (2) things that brought me joy (some things were both, some were only one); plus, be very conscious when I chose to do things I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do (but maybe had to).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to my 20s</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/letter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/letter-29/</guid>
      <description>Dear early-20s-me, May you find some encouragement in these words, that they may ease your journey a little. But also feel free to ignore anything and everything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t land!
To the big questions on self-discovery and meaning and fulfillment, unfortunately it looks like there might not be any actual succinct answers, not really. There&amp;rsquo;s only the journey, there&amp;rsquo;s only the present. I know this sounds vague as shit, but it&amp;rsquo;s starting to sink in for me more and more I think.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/comparisons/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;This guy has literally been pumping out writing, consistently, for 10 years. And here I am with my scatterbrained 14 blog posts, I have so far to go to even get to some semblance of competence.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I wish I practiced piano more when I was a kid.&amp;rdquo;
There are of course comparisons that are positive and productive, ones that are feather-light and don&amp;rsquo;t cause any feeling of tighness in the chest, yet they expand our taste or reveal something to us to get us unstuck.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journaling on: Work</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/journal-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 16:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/journal-work/</guid>
      <description>I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m wasting away.
I spend ~10 hours each weekday within the world of Work, and I no longer enjoy it (but oh how I used to!). I scramble around, I&amp;rsquo;m in meetings, I help with planning, I get pinged and pulled into conversatons. I get annoyed with people and their incompetence, and my incompetence. I avoid the work I need to do (Why? Don&amp;rsquo;t want to face reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022: Year In Review</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/2022-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/2022-review/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I&amp;rsquo;m starting to realize as I get older is that I have an absolutely abysmal memory.
Like, my brain is terrible at storing thoughts and experiences into long-term memory. (My working theory is that this is an adaptation to my overactive brain incessantly running and making connections. So lots of signals come in and then must immediately get chucked once they&amp;rsquo;re done with in order to save on RAM, and only certain things make it to deep storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Losing Weight</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/losing-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/losing-weight/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently writing this post in Singapore, at the beginning of a vacation in Southeast Asia to attend my close friends&amp;rsquo; wedding, and also to enjoy lots and lots of yummy food (Hainanese chicken rice, curry chicken noodles, kaya toast, nasi lemak, mee goreng, roti canai, chili crab, etc.).
Prior to the trip I&amp;rsquo;d finally started making consistent progress on losing some weight. I reached a low of 180 lbs, a milestone I&amp;rsquo;d only been able to hit a few times in the last 10 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSR, and the Credit Card Game</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/csr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/csr/</guid>
      <description>The US credit card game is a fun little optimization problem where the rewards can include free* travel, fancy hotel stays, and first-class flights.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example subproblem from the midgame.
Downgrading my Chase Sapphire Reserve Why? I&amp;rsquo;m paying to keep the Reserve (or CSR) and I&amp;rsquo;m not getting enough value out of it for what I&amp;rsquo;m paying. And I can downgrade the card to a Freedom Flex which has no annual fee (meaning I can replace this expensive card with a no-cost one, without needing to cancel the card).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning 30</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/turning-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/turning-30/</guid>
      <description>All the worry floating around in the public consciousness around Turning 30 was always so confusing to me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it. It felt like a meme. Like everyone was afraid of the concept of 30; because everyone older than you had also been afraid of turning 30.
Whenever I asked friends about it, why they got chills even coming to the realization that we were no longer in our mid-twenties but now in our late-twenties (meaning: almost 30), the answer was always something vague and unsatisfying like &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be 30&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;then I&amp;rsquo;ll be old&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;life ends at 30&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Brain and Ego</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/brain-and-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/brain-and-ego/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished reading What Happened To You?, a dialogue between Oprah and Bruce Perry, a psychiatrist who specializes in understanding adverse childhood experiences and trauma and how they impact human behaviour.
Besides offering an invaluable reframe from asking &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with you?&amp;rdquo; to asking &amp;ldquo;what happened to you?&amp;rdquo; when trying to understand why we might behave or react in the ways we do, another huge takeaway for me was the neurosequential model of the brain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taxes and Supplemental Income</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/taxes/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip worth a thousand dollars: if you earned supplemental income in the US, then you may owe (a lot) more taxes on it than you think.
TL;DR: for high earners, especially those with stock grants in a public company, there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between &amp;ldquo;taxes withheld&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;taxes owed&amp;rdquo; on supplemental income, and you&amp;rsquo;re responsible for paying that difference. This can be as high as an extra 15% in taxes (!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My brain on NFTs, Dec 2021</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/nfts-dec-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/nfts-dec-2021/</guid>
      <description>I spent a sizable chunk of my December diving into NFTs and NFT communities. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to, beyond maybe doing some cursory digging into smart contracts and trying to understand what &amp;ldquo;web3&amp;rdquo; actually meant (feels prudent, idk). But NFTs turned out to be one of those vortexes that latched onto me and just didn&amp;rsquo;t let go. I turned into that guy in my friend circle.
And NFTs are becoming more than just an online-only fad or a hobbyist thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Leisurely Weekend</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/a-leisurely-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 23:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/a-leisurely-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I spent the past weekend in absolute satisfaction. In Flow. Time rushed by, yet I was immersed in each moment. I cooked multiple meals with my roommate (Indian bread rolls and Bombay sandwiches), started and finished season 1 of Ted Lasso, played tennis, and watched the Come From Away musical. I even had time to run some errands, draw, zoom call a twitter friend, and redecorate my apartment a little.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Games Are Fun</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/competitive-games-are-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/competitive-games-are-fun/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;This game is bullsh*t!&amp;rdquo;
Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s played video games competitively (League of Legends, Counter-Strike, Fortnite, Street Fighter, etc.) has yelled this into the void at least once. Maybe you were having an off game, maybe your teammates looked like they had no clue what they were doing, or maybe you got stomped by your opponent and you had no idea what you could&amp;rsquo;ve done differently to win.
Go through this experience enough times (and you will end up here, a lot, given enough time) and you start to question all the hours you&amp;rsquo;ve put in, grinding solo queue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food-Efficient: Pour-Over Coffee</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/coffee/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I attended a wonderful Interintellect Salon on Talking about Money, where we talked about everything from the philosophy of money, to why there seems to be so much financial illiteracy, to the credit card ecosystem, to the US Tax Code.
A recurring point was that good financial advice can be hard to find, and you might not even know where to start looking. And personal finance has been something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to write about for a while now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Week: VTubers</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/vtubers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 01:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/vtubers/</guid>
      <description>I recently stumbled upon the phenomenon of VTubers, and honestly I&amp;rsquo;m a bit obsessed.
&amp;quot;Eekum bokum.&amp;quot;
-Inugami Korone, 2020 pic.twitter.com/DEL4krzKFy
&amp;mdash; Tylor (@theSirToasty) September 1, 2020 VTubers, short for Virtual YouTubers, are what you&amp;rsquo;d get if anime characters suddenly came to life and also became Content Creators. They&amp;rsquo;re real people playing a persona using digital, anime-like avatars (not to be confused with influencers that are CGI + ML models). With 3D animation and face/body tracking tech, VTubers livestream themselves hanging out and chatting, playing games, singing, and sometimes collabing with other VTubers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exponential Growth, and Viruses</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/exponential-growth-and-viruses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 19:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/exponential-growth-and-viruses/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;On Day 1 you start with 1 penny. On Day 2 you double it and have 2 pennies. On Day 3 you double that and have 4 pennies. Repeat. How much money do you have on Day 30?&amp;rdquo;
Most people have been asked this question at one point or another.
It’s memorable; in part because the idea of doubling the size of your bank account day after day sounds like something you’d sign up for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo - Food, Coffee, Games</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/tokyo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/tokyo-2019/</guid>
      <description>2023 Update: Check out my latest recs here!
In the span of two weeks, 3 friends asked me for Tokyo recommendations from my trip earlier this year. So I&amp;rsquo;m putting those recommendations here as a sort of log / for future reference.
Here are some general tips on how to travel to Tokyo. The rest is all about food, coffeeshops, and games (the majority of time spent during my recent trip).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Minimum Viable Blog</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/minimum-viable-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 22:26:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/minimum-viable-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by how great writers can break apart complex systems, stir up emotions, and build worlds. Writing is an especially important skill now, as we live and breathe email, iMessage, and Slack. Where you can find friends, and even a tribe, solely via Twitter.
As with anything I find interesting, I wanted to try doing it myself. With writing, though, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure where or how to start.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:54:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a first post!
In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a bit about me and here are some of my favourite links.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
