<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>debug sab on Billy&#39;s Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in debug sab on Billy&#39;s Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 23:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #9: Good Work</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 23:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/9/</guid>
      <description>This past May, I started feeling like I&amp;rsquo;d been doing Fun Projects for long enough. Since July 2023 I&amp;rsquo;d been fighting (with love) my urge/anxiety around needing to feel productive, make money, and get back to self-sufficiency, by reconnecting to my sense of Fun and doing Fun Projects.1 But after ~10 months of this, I was feeling a bit hedonistic, and I was suddenly motivated again to work on my career.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #8: Year One</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/8/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been just over one year now since I went on sabbatical, and I wanted to write some sort of &amp;ldquo;Year One&amp;rdquo; update post. But what I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to happen was for me to get stuck making something Serious or Formal in order to Properly celebrate the milestone. So here I am, writing something quick and loose so I can just get something out into the world.
A quick summary of my one year on sabbatical:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #7: Learning How To Be Happy</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/7/</guid>
      <description>Up until a month ago, I would explain what I was doing on sabbatical by telling people something like &amp;ldquo;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m going to the gym, and then besides that I&amp;rsquo;m mostly doing fun creative projects like writing, drawing, and playing the drums.&amp;rdquo; Because that&amp;rsquo;s what I did. For the past few months, from Feb thru May, all I focused on was getting into a rhythm again of Doing Stuff that I enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #6: Is This It?</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/6/</guid>
      <description>Writing my previous blog post took a lot out of me, to the point where I started looking forward to being done with the post halfway through the writing process. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I wrote it, but I&amp;rsquo;m also glad it&amp;rsquo;s over with. After publishing the post, I took a week off from writing. I still drew portrait studies and practiced the drums, but I filled the extra time with books, video games, and… just pondering what else to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #5: Self-Love</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 23:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/5/</guid>
      <description>Covers Nov 2023 to Jan 2024.
After the dust settled in October, my experiences and my new mindset coalesced into these two goals:
Continue to do the creative work that I love, and do whatever I need to in order to sustain this; while in the background:
Rewire myself away from grasping for external validation of my work as a necessary component of my worth, and toward cultivating an internal wellspring of self-worth</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical: July - October</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/recap1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/recap1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on sabbatical since July now. And up until October, something new would shift for me literally every two weeks. This post is intended to be a record of all of those changes, so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget this crazy, wonderful time.
The timeline
How it started July Week 1-2 - Objective #1 - Find a more fulfilling way to work Getting another perspective - Give Your Gift Week 3-4 - Objective #2 - Reconnect with Fun August Week 1-2 - Objective #3 - Meander The neutral zone Week 3-4 - A door appears September Week 1-2 - Descend Week 3-4 - Emerge October Objective #4 - Keep doing creative work How it started ↩︎</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #4: October</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/4/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been chipping away at a big post to map out how my thinking has changed since the start of my sabbatical in July (edit: out now!). But I&amp;rsquo;ve also been getting antsy about not having published anything in over a month. So here&amp;rsquo;s an update for October!
Do The Thing &amp;ldquo;Do The Thing&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Do 100 Reps&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Just Do It&amp;rdquo;
This idea has been like a scalpel for me, continuing to cut through my bullshit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #3: Goals</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/3/</guid>
      <description>While updating my Now Page, I got to thinking about how I would describe what I&amp;rsquo;d like to accomplish on my sabbatical. I wanted a clear-cut answer to a question I&amp;rsquo;d been asking myself for the past two months now: &amp;ldquo;What am I doing? Where is this going?&amp;rdquo;
Here&amp;rsquo;s the excerpt I came up with:
I&amp;rsquo;d love to eventually carve out a way of living and working that&amp;rsquo;s more satisfying for me than my prior experience with the typical corporate path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #2</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/2-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/2-fun/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Everyone has a plan until they get punched in the mouth.&amp;rdquo; - Mike Tyson, modified
Planning is everything, but plans mean nothing. And oh boy did my initial plans go out the window quickly.
The top projects I&amp;rsquo;d planned to work on were: coaching setup stuff, writing blog posts, and writing fiction. But when I started to actually spend time on these things, I found myself feeling kinda miserable. What the heck?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical Notes #1</title>
      <link>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/1-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://billy.dev/posts/sabbatical-notes/1-doing/</guid>
      <description>Doing the thing I&amp;rsquo;m officially on sabbatical!
I started my leave from work on June 5, but I immediately went on a 2-week vacation to Tokyo. Now I&amp;rsquo;m settled back in, and getting to work. And so, in July 2023, it really begins.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written previously about what I&amp;rsquo;d like to accomplish during my little incubator: in short, writing a lot and starting up some form of tech career coaching. But two weeks in and I already feel a bit unmoored.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
